[music]
>> Welcome to yet another video on things
we did to make the MCP server for
Business Central even better.
In this video, I will show you how you
can use all the APIs that Microsoft
provides for Business Central in your
agents built on MCP server.
What this means is that the surface of
Business Central is just much larger
now.
You can use
MCP server not only for the core APIs in
V2 that was kind of how it was until
April 2026,
but now everything like subscription
billing or e-invoicing,
automation APIs, everything that has an
API is now enabled for MCP server and
therefore for your agents. So, just to
recap, in the April release of 2026 wave
one,
things highlighted in italic is what we
shipped there and now we are adding
these two new things. This video is
about supporting all the Microsoft APIs.
There's another video for supporting API
queries and I think you should watch
both of these to kind of get
your agents the full power of what we're
releasing in 28.2.
Yeah, so as I mentioned,
all Microsoft published APIs are
available in MCP server.
Let's Let me just quickly show you how
you set that up in the MCP server
configuration.
So, as you probably know, there are
multiple ways to add
APIs to an MCP server configuration. You
can either go and add them one by one or
just use the action add tools by API
group. Let me just do that.
And if I type in Microsoft or just
, let's see what now happens.
You see I get all the API groups, not
only the the version two one.
So, here you can see analytics,
automation APIs, e-document,
intercompany,
um
everything that we have an API group for
is now available.
So, if I choose okay here and just
choose automation APIs,
here I just added all the automation
APIs. And of course, I can make them
something else than read only if they
support
that if they are not read only by
default.
So, that's it. Now, to get to
understand which APIs are available, the
standard documentation for this in our
developer documentation is
has this landing page
aka.ms/bcintegration.
And if you
then dive in
that part of our Microsoft Learn under
APIs, you you see all the APIs um
documented there, so you can learn more
about them. You might even want to have
your agents use some of this
documentation as knowledge to understand
more what these APIs are capable of.
That's it. If you want to know more
about everything related to MCP server
for Business Central, we have a playlist
for that. That playlist you find under
our YouTube channel aka.ms/bcyoutube.
Find
Go navigate to the playlist, and then
here the playlist getting started with
MCP server. This video is there. The
other video on
The queries is there, and and the old
videos for the from the previous
releases are there as well.
If you want to dive more into MCP server
and haven't done any of this before,
there is also a landing page for that
for Microsoft Learn. It is aka.ms/bcmcp.
And
hopefully that together with the new
APIs will enable you to identify
much more of the ERP workloads for your
environment or for your customers if you
are a partner.
And that's it.
Before you
dive into actually like making agents
left and right, make sure you that you
watch the other video for API queries in
MCP server. The link is in the
description for this video or just go to
the playlist on everything related to
MCP.
That's it. Have a great day. Thank you.